Register of the Poland. Ministerstwo Spraw Zagranicznych Records, 1919-1947.
Hoover Institution Archives
- SERIES NO. 48. INSTRUCTIONS OF MINISTRY
  - 1931
    - Circulation of classified materials. Typescript (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Military staff training. Memorandum. Mimeograph (Folder 2)
  - 1943 (Folder 3)
  - 1944 (Folder 4)
- SERIES NO. 49. POLITICAL RELATIONS WITH POLAND IN GENERAL
  - 1920-1935
    - Embezzlement of state property (Nowacki affair), 1920-1921 (Folder 5)
    - Report from Polish ambassador to Great Britain to Jozef Beck, 1930 (Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1931 (Folder 7)
    - City of Wilno, Loan of 1912, 1931 (Folder 8)
    - Polish-Austrian Chamber of Commerce, 1931 (Folder 9)
    - Bilateral agreement on financial compensations between Poland and Romania, 1932 (Folder 10)
    - Krupp syndicate and Soviet defense industry. Report from Consulate in Essen, 1932 (Folder 11)
    - Polish-Soviet relations, 1932-1934 (Folder 12)
    - International Convention on Definition of Aggression, London, 1933 (Folder 13)
    - Memorandum from Italian government to Polish government, 1933 (Folder 14)
    - Polish-German relations, 1933-1934 (Folder 15)
    - Ministry's report on international situation in Europe, 1935 (Folder 16)
    - Neutrality of Baltic Sea, 1935 (Folder 17)
    - Report of De Vries from Berlin, 1935 (Folder 18)
  - 1938, September. Correspondence between Edvard Benes and Ignacy Moscicki (Folder 19)
  - 1939
    - Notes on relations with France, November (Folder 20)
    - Lithuania. Notes and reports, Oct.-Dec. (Folder 21)
    - Soviet-Lithuanian-Polish relations, Oct.-Nov. (Folder 22)
    - List of documents contained in SERIES NO. 49, covering period 1932-1939 (Folder 23)
  - 1940
    - Belgium (Folder 24)
    - Brazil and South America (Folder 25)
    - British India (Folder 26)
    - Canada (Folder 27)
    - Chile (Folder 28)
    - Czechoslovakia
      - General (Folder 29)
      - Assistance to Czechoslovak citizens and government by Polish diplomacy (Folder 30)
      - International recognition of Czechoslovak government (Folder 31)
      - Memoranda of Edvard Benes, Feb.-Dec. (Folder 32)
      - Notes on Polish-Czechoslovak relations (Folder 33)
      - Polish-Czechoslovak Fedederation (Proposed), Aug.-Nov. (Folder 34)
      - Polish-Czechoslovak Federation Coordination Committee, Feb.-Dec. (Folder 35)
      - Polish-Czechoslovak rapprochement and idea of federation, Oct.-Nov. (Folder 36)
      - Polish-Czechoslovak rapprochement in the United States, June-Nov. (Folder 37)
      - Talks and correspondence with former minister Hodza (Folder 38)
      - Talks with Edvard Benes, Aug.-Sept. (Folder 39)
      - Top secret (Folder 40)
    - Finland (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - France
      - General (Folder 2)
      - Top secret. Detailed report on internal conditions and relations with Poland (Folder 3)
    - Germany (Folder 4)
    - Great Britain
      - General (Folder 5)
      - Correspondence with Ernest Bevin (Folder 6)
      - Employment for Polish citizens (Folder 7)
      - Letters from Anthony Eden and Lord Halifax (Folder 8)
      - Letters to Lord Halifax (Folder 9)
      - Top secret (Folder 10)
    - Greece (Folder 11)
    - Hungary (Folder 12)
    - Italy (Folder 13)
    - Japan (Folder 14)
    - Lithuania (Folder 15)
    - Netherlands (Folder 16)
    - Romania
      - General (Folder 17)
      - "Akcja Tilea" (Folder 18)
    - Soviet Union
      - General (Folder 19)
      - General Staff report (Folder 20)
    - Spain (Folder 21)
    - Sweden (Folder 22)
    - Switzerland (Folder 23)
    - United Sates
      - General (Folder 24)
      - Nomination of Ambassador Jan Ciechanowski (Folder 25)
      - 1941 (Box 39)
      - Yugoslavia (Folder 26)
    - Afghanistan (Folder 1)
    - Australia (Folder 2)
    - Belgium (Folder 3)
    - Brazil (Folder 4)
    - Bulgaria (Folder 5)
    - Canada (Folder 6)
    - Chile (Folder 7)
    - China (Folder 8)
    - Colombia (Folder 9)
    - Czechoslovakia
      - General
        - Jan.-March (Folder 10)
        - Apr.-June (Folder 11)
        - July-Sept. (Folder 12)
        - Oct.-Dec. (Folder 13)
      - Agreement on diplomatic correspondence (Folder 14)
      - Diplomatic recognition of Czechoslovakia (Folder 15)
      - Federation
        - Coordination Committee (Folder 16)
        - Ministers Council Political Committee (Folder 17)
        - Memorandum of Edvard Benes (Folder 18)
        - Top secret (Folder 19)
    - Egypt (Folder 20)
    - Finland (Folder 21)
    - France (Box 40)
      - General (Folder 1)
      - Free French (Folder 2)
      - Syria (Folder 3)
      - Vichy (Folder 4)
    - Germany (Folder 5)
    - Great Britain
      - General
        - Jan.-June (Folder 6)
        - July-Dec. (Folder 7)
      - London International Assembly (Folder 8)
    - Greece (Folder 9)
    - Hungary (Folder 10)
    - Iceland (Folder 11)
    - Iran (Folder 12)
    - Ireland (Folder 13)
    - Italy
      - General (Folder 14)
      - Top secret (Folder 15)
    - Japan (Folder 16)
    - Latin America (Folder 17)
    - Latvia (Folder 18)
    - Lithuania
      - Jan.-Apr. (Folder 19)
      - May-Aug. (Box 41, Folder 1)
      - Sept.-Dec. (Folder 2)
    - Luxemburg (Folder 3)
    - Netherlands (Folder 4)
    - Norway (Folder 5)
    - Portugal (Folder 6)
    - Romania
      - General (Folder 7)
      - "Akcja Tilea" (Folder 8)
      - Carol, King. Escape from Spain (Folder 9)
    - South Africa (Folder 10)
    - Soviet Union
      - General (Folder 11)
      - Diplomatic notes (Folder 12)
      - Instructions (Folder 13)
      - Polish-Soviet agreement (Folder 14)
      - Polish-Soviet declaration (Folder 15)
      - Question of Poland's eastern borders (Folder 16)
      - Restoration of diplomatic relations (Folder 17)
    - Spain (Folder 18)
    - Sweden (Folder 19)
    - Turkey (Folder 20)
    - United States (Box 42)
      - General
        - Jan.-June (Folder 1)
        - July-Dec. (Folder 2)
      - Lend-lease Act (Folder 3)
      - Mikolajczyk, Stanislaw. Trip (Folder 4)
      - Sikorski, Wladyslaw. Trip
        - General (Folder 5)
        - Briefings on Poland's political position (Folder 6)
        - Canadian stop (Folder 7)
        - Chicago visit (Folder 8)
        - Detroit visit (Folder 9)
        - New York visit (Folder 10)
        - Washington visit (Folder 11)
        - Polish-American press (Folder 12)
        - Press reaction (various sources) (Folder 13)
        - Roosevelt, Franklin D. Memorandum (Folder 14)
        - Telegrams (Folder 15)
    - Yugoslavia (Folder 16)
    - 1942 (Box 43)
    - Abyssinia (Folder 1)
    - Argentina (Folder 2)
    - Australia (Folder 3)
    - Baltic states
      - Estonia (Folder 4)
      - Latvia (Folder 5)
      - Lithuania
        - General
          - Jan.-June (Folder 6)
          - July-Dec. (Folder 7)
        - Ministry of Interior reports (Folder 8)
        - Jedrzejewski office reports (Folder 9)
    - Belgium (Folder 10)
    - Brazil (Folder 11)
    - Canada (Folder 12)
    - Central Europe. Top secret (Folder 13)
    - Chile (Folder 14)
    - China (Folder 15)
    - Colombia (Folder 16)
    - Cuba (Folder 17)
    - Czechoslovakia (Box 44)
      - General
        - Jan.-June (Folder 1)
        - July-Dec. (Folder 2)
      - British policy (Folder 3)
      - Slask Cieszynski (Folder 4)
      - Top secret (Folder 5)
    - Dominican Republic (Folder 6)
    - Ecuador (Folder 7)
    - Egypt
      - General (Folder 8)
      - Top secret (Folder 9)
    - Finland (Folder 10)
    - France
      - General (Folder 11)
      - American occupation of French North Africa (Folder 12)
      - Border negotiations between Poland and Czechoslovakia (Folder 13)
      - Free French
        - General (Folder 14)
        - Top secret (Folder 15)
    - Germany
      - General (Folder 16)
      - Komisja d/s Niemieckich (German Affairs Commission) (Folder 17)
      - Top secret (Folder 18)
    - Great Britain
      - General (Folder 19)
      - Top secret
        - General (Folder 20)
        - Note to Anthony Eden (Folder 21)
        - Memoranda on Polish-Soviet relations (Folder 22)
    - Greece. See also SERIES NO. 598 (Folder 23)
    - Hungary
      - General (Folder 24)
      - Top secret (Folder 25)
    - Iraq (Folder 26)
    - Ireland (Folder 27)
    - Italy
      - General (Folder 28)
      - Top secret (Folder 29)
    - Japan
      - General (Folder 30)
      - Top secret (Folder 31)
    - Mexico (Folder 32)
    - Norway (Folder 33)
    - Pact of the Eight. Preliminary talks. Top secret (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Panama (Folder 2)
    - Peru (Folder 3)
    - Portugal (Folder 4)
    - Romania
      - General (Folder 5)
      - Top secret (Folder 6)
    - Slovakia (Folder 7)
    - South Africa (Folder 8)
    - South America (Folder 9)
    - Soviet Union
      - General (Folder 10)
      - "Akcja sowiecko-komunistyczna w Polsce", July 1. Typescript (Folder 11)
      - Ambassador Waclaw Podoski's interview on Soviet-German relations (Folder 12)
      - American ambassador to (Folder 13)
      - Border line dispute (Folder 14)
      - Closing of diplomatic representations (Folder 15)
      - Correspondence between foreign ministers of Poland and Soviet Union (Folder 16)
      - Demands for release from imprisonment (Folder 17)
      - Instructions (Folder 18)
      - Loans (Folder 19)
      - Memorandum on Polish-Soviet relations, July 30 (Folder 20)
      - Passport issues (Folder 21)
      - Polish army in (Folder 22)
      - Polish citizens of non-Polish nationality (Folder 23)
      - "Polityka Polska wobec Rosji, 1921-1941". Typescript (Folder 24)
      - "Polska a Rosja". Outline of Polish-Soviet relations, 1921-1941. Typescript (Folder 25)
      - Sikorski, Wladyslaw, General
        - Memorandum of November 19 (Folder 26)
        - Trip to (Folder 27)
      - Responses to inquiries on fate of Polish officers (Folder 28)
      - Talks with Soviet officials (Folder 29)
      - Territorial dispute with Poland. Reaction from abroad (Folder 30)
      - Turkey, Soviet Ambassador to (Folder 31)
    - Spain (Box 46)
      - General (Folder 1)
      - Controversies related to functioning of Polish Legation (Folder 2)
      - Correspondence of ambassador (Folder 3)
      - Diplomatic intervention on behalf of Poland (Folder 4)
      - Liquidation of Polish Mission (Folder 5)
      - Personnel of Polish Mission (Folder 6)
      - Refugees and Polish raison d'etat (Folder 7)
      - Top secret (Folder 8)
    - Sweden (Folder 9)
    - Syria and Lebanon (Folder 10)
    - Turkey
      - General (Folder 11)
      - Top secret (Folder 12)
    - Ukraine. Top secret (Folder 13)
    - United States
      - General (Folder 14)
      - Ciechanowski, Jan. Reports (Folder 15)
      - Coded messages to embassy (Folder 16)
      - Foreign minister's trip (Folder 17)
      - Lend-lease agreement (Folder 18)
      - Loans (Folder 19)
      - Polish-American cooperation agreement (Folder 20)
      - Sikorski, Wladyslaw, General
        - Second trip (Folder 21)
        - Third trip (Folder 22)
    - Uruguay (Folder 23)
    - Venezuela (Folder 24)
    - Yugoslavia
      - General (Folder 25)
      - Top secret (Folder 26)
    - 1943 (Box 47)
    - "Akcja kontynentalna". Top secret (Folder 1)
    - Afghanistan (Folder 2)
    - Argentina (Folder 3)
    - Australia (Folder 4)
    - Balkan states. Top secret (Folder 5)
    - Baltic states (Folder 6)
    - Belgium
      - General (Folder 7)
      - Polish-Belgian agreement (Folder 8)
    - Bolivia
      - General (Folder 9)
      - Top secret (Folder 10)
    - Brazil (Folder 11)
    - British India (Folder 12)
    - Canada (Folder 13)
    - Central Europe. Top secret (Folder 14)
    - Chile (Folder 15)
    - China
      - General (Folder 16)
      - Top secret (Folder 17)
    - Colombia (Folder 18)
    - Cuba (Folder 19)
    - Czechoslovakia
      - Benes, Edvard and Polish-Soviet relations (Folder 20)
      - Border dispute (Folder 21)
      - Clippings from Polish press (Folder 22)
      - Diplomatic notes (Folder 23)
      - Mussolini, Benito. Fall (Folder 24)
      - "Plan for Insurgent Movements and Surface Thrusts". Secret document on necessity of coordinating insurgent movements in Europe. Mimeograph (Folder 25)
      - Relations with Poland (Folder 26)
      - Relations with Polish diplomatic representations (Folder 27)
      - Slask Cieszynski (Folder 28)
      - Talks of Edward Raczynski with Edvard Benes and Tomas Masaryk (Folder 29)
      - Top secret
        - General (Folder 30)
        - Telegrams (Folder 31)
    - Dominican Republic (Folder 32)
    - Egypt (Folder 33)
    - France (Free French) (Box 48)
      - General
        - Jan.-June (Folder 1)
        - July-Dec. (Folder 2)
      - Coded messages (Folder 3)
      - Giraud, Henri, General (Folder 4)
      - National Liberation Committee
        - General (Folder 5)
        - Top secret
          - General (Folder 6)
          - Polish-Soviet relations. Memorandum for French government (Folder 7)
          - Reports on internal situation (Folder 8)
          - Sugestie dla sojusznikow. Note by Ministry of Interior on French collaborationism (Folder 9)
    - Germany
      - General (Folder 10)
      - Anti-Polish propaganda (Folder 11)
      - Clippings from Polish press (Folder 12)
      - Miedzyministerialna Komisja d/s Niemieckich (Folder 13)
      - Polish consular representatives in East Prussia in 1939 (Folder 14)
      - Top secret
        - General (Folder 15)
        - Peace negotiations (Folder 16)
        - Plans toward Poland (Folder 17)
      - Upper Silesia
        - Register of documents in possession of Montreal representation (Folder 18)
        - Resettlement plans (Folder 19)
    - Great Britain
      - General (Folder 20)
      - Anglo-American demarche, Aug. 11 (Folder 21)
      - British dominions (Folder 22)
      - British parliament (Folder 23)
      - Clippings from Polish press (Folder 24)
      - Eden, Anthony
        - Talks and speeches (Folder 25)
        - Washington trip (Folder 26)
      - Low's cartoon (Folder 27)
      - Memoranda of Polish government (Folder 28)
      - Polish-British relations (Folder 29)
      - Polish-Soviet relations (Folder 30)
      - Propaganda among youth movement (Folder 31)
      - Talks with British officials (Folder 32)
      - Top secret (Folder 33)
    - Hungary. Top secret (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Greece (Folder 2)
    - Iran
      - General (Folder 3)
      - Top secret (Folder 4)
    - Iraq (Folder 5)
    - Ireland (Folder 6)
    - Italy
      - General (Folder 7)
      - Assistance to Polish war refugees (Folder 8)
      - Polish military mission (Folder 9)
      - Top secret (Folder 10)
    - Japan. Top secret (Folder 11)
    - Lithuania
      - General (Folder 12)
      - Coded messages (Folder 13)
      - International press views (Folder 14)
      - Linia z dnia 8 XII 1919 i "Linia Curzona" z dnia 11 VII 1920. Typescript report (Folder 15)
      - Lithuanians in the United States (Folder 16)
      - Raport specjalny w sprawach narodowosciowych, April (Folder 17)
      - Reports
        - Diplomatic sources (Folder 18)
        - Government agencies (Folder 19)
        - Stockholm Legation (Folder 20)
        - Washington Embassy (Folder 21)
    - Mexico
      - General (Folder 22)
      - Top secret (Folder 23)
    - Netherlands
      - General (Folder 24)
      - Top secret (Folder 25)
    - Norway (Folder 26)
    - Palestine
      - Army deserters (Folder 27)
      - Top secret. Jewish soldiers in the Polish army (Folder 28)
    - Paraguay (Folder 29)
    - Peru (Folder 30)
    - Portugal (Folder 31)
    - Rhodesia (Folder 32)
    - Romania
      - General (Folder 33)
      - Top secret (Folder 34)
    - Slovakia (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - South Africa (Folder 2)
    - South America
      - General (Folder 3)
      - Top secret (Folder 4)
    - Soviet Union
      - Biala Ksiega (White Book). Documents
        - General (Folder 5)
        - Army evacuation (Folder 6)
        - Breaking of diplomatic relations (Folder 7)
        - Decree of citizenship (Folder 8)
        - Diplomatic notes (Folder 9)
        - English translation (Folder 10)
        - First typed edition (Folder 11)
        - Free Europe, April issues (Folder 12)
        - List of documents to be included in publication (Folder 13)
        - Polish-Soviet talks
          - General (Folder 14)
          - Romer-Molotov
            - Holograph (Folder 15)
            - Typescript (Folder 16)
          - Romer-Stalin (Folder 17)
          - Sikorski-Kot-Stalin (Folder 18)
        - White Russia. Geographical terminology (Folder 19)
      - Biala Ksiega. Typescript (Box 51)
        - Copy 1 (Folder 1)
        - Copy 2 (Folder 2)
        - Copy 3 (Folder 3)
        - Copy 4 (Folder 4)
        - Copy 5 (Box 52, Folder 1)
        - Supplement. Speech of General Wladyslaw Sikorski in Moscow, Dec. 4 (Folder 2)
      - Border conflict
        - General (Folder 3)
        - Declaration of Polish government, Feb. 25 (Folder 4)
        - Foreign press
          - Reports (Folder 5)
          - Telegrams (Folder 6)
        - Letters to top Soviet officials (Folder 7)
        - Reaction of emigre circles (Folder 8)
        - Soviet decrees on annexation (Folder 9)
        - Soviet maps (Folder 10)
        - U.S. involvement (Folder 11)
      - Breaking of diplomatic relations. Press comments
        - China (Folder 12)
        - Emigre circles (Folder 13)
        - Europe (Folder 14)
        - New Zealand (Folder 15)
        - North America (Folder 16)
        - South Africa (Folder 17)
        - South America (Folder 18)
      - Closing of Polish relief institutions (Box 53, Folder 1)
      - Diplomatic correspondence (Folder 2)
      - Diplomatic notes on Soviet citizenship (Folder 3)
      - Loan for Polish army (Folder 4)
      - Memoranda of Polish government (Folder 5)
      - Moscow negotiations
        - Reports to the minister (Folder 6)
        - Telegrams (Folder 7)
      - Most secret. Talks with Sokolin (Folder 8)
      - Passport and Polish citizenship issues (Folder 9)
      - Press comments
        - International (Folder 10)
        - Polish press in Great Britain (Folder 11)
      - Soviet propaganda
        - Brazil (Folder 12)
        - Great Britain (Folder 13)
        - United States (Folder 14)
        - Other countries (Folder 15)
      - Talks
        - Raczynski, Edward - Bogomolov, Aleksander (Folder 16)
        - Romer, Tadeusz - Molotov, Viacheslav (Folder 17)
      - Top secret
        - Diplomatic relations with Poland (Folder 18)
        - Military issues (Folder 19)
        - Notes (Folder 20)
        - Soviet citizenship and relief action (Folder 21)
      - Uzasadnienie granicy wschodniej panstwa Polskiego, London, September. Mimeograph (Folder 22)
    - Spain
      - General (Folder 23)
      - Top secret
        - General (Folder 24)
        - Dubicz-Penther, H. Report on talks with Spanish ambassador (Folder 25)
    - Sweden
      - General (Folder 26)
      - Top secret
        - General (Folder 27)
        - Future economic relations with Poland (Folder 28)
    - Switzerland (Folder 29)
    - Turkey
      - General (Folder 30)
      - Top secret
        - General (Folder 31)
        - Correspondence between M. Sokolnicki and T. Romer (Folder 32)
    - United States (Box 54)
      - General (Folder 1)
      - Ciechanowski, Jan. Reports (Folder 2)
      - Coded messages (Folder 3)
      - Office of War Information (Folder 4)
      - Sikorski, Wladyslaw, General. Trip (Folder 5)
      - Top secret
        - General (Folder 6)
        - Ciechanowski, Jan. Reports
          - May-July (Folder 7)
          - Aug.-Nov. Contains report on Jan Karski's visit to the White House and talks with F. Roosevelt (Folder 8)
        - Coded messages (Folder 9)
    - Ukraine. Top secret (Folder 10)
    - Uruguay (Folder 11)
    - Vatican. Top secret (Folder 12)
    - Venezuela (Folder 13)
    - Yugoslavia
      - General (Folder 14)
      - Top secret (Folder 15)
      - 1944 (Box 55)
    - Abyssinia (Folder 1)
    - Algeria. Top secret. Polish gold (Folder 2)
    - Argentina (Folder 3)
    - Australia (Folder 4)
    - Baltic states
      - General (Folder 5)
      - Lithuania
        - General (Folder 6)
        - Intelligence reports (Folder 7)
        - Press (Folder 8)
        - Reports
          - Ottawa Consulate General (Folder 9)
          - Stockholm Legation (Folder 10)
          - United States. Various sources, mainly Washington Embassy (Folder 11)
          - Vatican Embassy (Folder 12)
        - Sworakowska, Helena. Correspondence on her treatise on Polish-Lithuanian relations (Folder 13)
    - Belgium (Folder 14)
    - Bolivia (Folder 15)
    - Brazil (Folder 16)
    - British India (Folder 17)
    - Bulgaria (Folder 18)
    - Canada
      - Consulates
        - Montreal (Folder 19)
        - Ottawa (Folder 20)
      - Correspondence with the prime minister of Canada (Folder 21)
      - Reports from Ottawa Consulate General
        - Babinski, W. (Folder 22)
        - Podoski, W.
          - General (Folder 23)
          - Radio speech (Folder 24)
    - Chile (Folder 25)
    - China
      - General (Folder 26)
      - Top secret (Folder 27)
    - Colombia (Folder 28)
    - Costa Rica (Folder 29)
    - Cuba (Folder 30)
    - Czechoslovakia
      - General (Folder 31)
      - Czechoslovak press (Folder 32)
      - Notes for the minister (Folder 33)
      - Pro-Soviet diplomacy (Folder 34)
      - Recruitment of Czech soldiers from German army in North Africa (Folder 35)
      - Reports from intelligence sources (Folder 36)
      - Slask Cieszynski (Folder 37)
    - Dominican Republic (Folder 38)
    - Ecuador (Folder 39)
    - Egypt
      - General (Folder 40)
      - Top secret (Folder 41)
    - Finland. Top secret (Folder 42)
    - France (Box 56)
      - General (Folder 1)
      - Coded messages (Folder 2)
      - Gaulle, Charles de, Correspondence with (Folder 3)
      - Komisja Miedzyministerialna d/s Francuskich, Oct.-Nov. (Folder 4)
      - Lublin government (Folder 5)
      - Newly-formed French government
        - Recognition (Folder 6)
        - Talks (Folder 7)
      - Polish diplomatic representation (Folder 8)
      - Polish-French relations (Folder 9)
      - Reports
        - Morawski, Jerzy (Folder 10)
        - Situation of Poles in France (Folder 11)
      - Top secret
        - General (Folder 12)
        - "Akcja Monika" (Folder 13)
        - Initiation of relations with Lublin Committee (Folder 14)
        - Messages for "Oskar" (Folder 15)
        - Political conditions. Reports (Folder 16)
        - Reports of Polish ambassador to France (Folder 17)
        - Situation of Poles in France (Folder 18)
    - Germany
      - Displaced persons in liberated territories (Folder 19)
      - German nationals in the Polish army (Folder 20)
      - German propaganda (Folder 21)
      - Miedzyministerialna Komisja d/s Niemieckich (Folder 22)
      - N.P.D. Press transmissions (Folder 23)
      - Possibility of Polish-German rapprochment (Folder 24)
      - Plans for Poland after Warsaw uprising (Folder 25)
      - Post-war borders (Folder 26)
    - Germany
      - Resettlement of Germans from Polish territory (Folder 27)
      - Status of Countries in Relation to the War (war declarations) (Folder 28)
      - Top secret
        - General (Folder 29)
        - Plans for Polish underground network (Folder 30)
        - Speculations on peace talks (Folder 31)
    - Great Britain
      - General (Folder 32)
      - Appeal of Scottish bishops (Folder 33)
      - Churchill, Winston. Speeches on Poland
        - February 22 (Folder 34)
        - December 15 (Folder 35)
      - Coded messages (Folder 36)
      - Lend-lease agreement (Folder 37)
      - National Council and violation of Atlantic Charter (Folder 38)
      - Notes for the minister (Folder 39)